# Álan Crístoffer e Sousa



**Personal Data** 33 years old, Brazilian

# **Contact** +33 6 20 48 95 86

acristoffers@startmail.com https://acristoffers.me

### Languages

Portuguese (native) English (C1) German (C1) French (B1)

#### **Skills**

System Analysis and Control, Android Development, Frontend, Backend, Embedded, Automation, Robotics

#### **Summary**

**Ph.D. Student** and **Master of Science** in Electrical Engineering, in the field of **Control Theory**, and **Mechatronic Engineer** with experience in **system analysis and control** and **programming**. Has worked in two scientific initiations building a platform that interfaces with hardware for system analysis and control objectives and learning Model Predictive Control.

#### **Experience**

2016–2016 Acal BFi Dietzenbach, Hessen, Germany

Intern

During this internship, I developed a platform to measure the power loss inside

the kernel of the inductor used in a PFC circuit.

2010–2013 **Corpo de Bombeiros Militar de Minas Gerais** Divinópolis, Minas Gerais, Brazil

Soldier

As a firefighter I was entitled to work as a first-aider and diver, being the first response in all sorts of accidents, from fire in the wilds to car accidents and

industrial and natural disasters.

#### **Education**

2021-	Ph.D. in Industrial Automation	Université de Reims Champagne-Ardene, France
	I'm working on attack detection and mitig	ation on cyber-physical systems.

2020–2020 Master in Electrical Engineering CEFET-MG/UFSJ, Brazil

I developed a switching-rule for constrained switched systems based on Region of Attraction under the supervision of Prof. Dr. Valter Leite and co-supervision of Prof. Dr.

Walter Lucia.

2013–2019 **Mechatronic Engineering** Centro Federal de Educação Tecnológica de Minas Gerais, Brazil

Since my first semester, I helped other students from graduation, master and Ph.D. with their projects, especially with programming. In my last year, I became the student

representative in the Graduation Council

2015–2016 **Student Exchange** Frankfurt University of Applied Sciences, Germany

I studied as an exchange student through the Brazilian government's program Ciências

Sem Fronteiras (Science Without Borders).

2015–2015 **Student Exchange** Université Grenoble Alpes, France

I studied as an exchange student through the partnership between UGA and CEFET-MG. There I worked in the robotics laboratory helping the team which won the second

place in the National Instruments MyRIO Paris competition.

#### **Interests**

**System Analysis and Control Theory** I worked with constrained switched systems and MPC. I studied non-linear and robust control, positive polynomials in control and complex networks. Now I'm working with attack detection on cyber-physical systems, researching the applicability of functional observers and time-scale systems for this end.

**Programming** C/C++, Python, Julia, Kotlin, Rust, Ruby, MATLAB...Languages are just tools in the belt. I can program using structured, object oriented and functional paradigms. I always try to use design patterns to make the code more organized and maintainable.

# **Extracurricular**

LAtiacuii	iculai	
2022	<b>Travaux Pratiques</b> Tutored a TP class entitled 'SY32: Practical Works on Linear State Space Control' where I tutored students with the use of MATLAB and Simulink for linear system analysis and sinthesis of controllers and observers.	
2021	<b>Travaux Pratiques</b> Tutored a TP class entitled 'Mobile Programming' where I tutored students with Android application development.	
2019	<b>BIC-Jr</b> Cosupervisor Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'Control of a coupled tanks system'.	
2019	<b>BIC-Jr</b> Cosupervisor Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'Modelling of an oven with space-distributed parameters'.	
2018	<b>BIC-Jr</b> Cosupervisor Cosupervised a junior scientific initiation entitled 'System modelling for process control'.	
2017 & 2018	<b>Python mini-course</b> I ministered a Python mini-course at my university. The textbook (in Portuguese) is freely available at https://acristoffers.me/Python3.pdf	
2017	<b>Semana C&amp;T - Week of Science and Technology</b> My project got the first place in the 13rd workshop at my university.	
2015	National Instruments MyRIO Compatition, Paris 2nd Place I helped the team that got the second place in the competition. I was responsible for the code interfacing with the camera and recognizing colors.	
2014	<b>Latin American Robotics Competition</b> I was part of the team that got the third place in the competition. I was responsible for the circuitry and programming of one of the robots.	
2014	Programming Tutoring I tutored students, helping them with assignments and teaching.	

# **Publications**

